Are you looking at naked tribeswomen?
你在看原住民裸女吗？
No,look.
不是，你看
That's a pig.
这是猪耶
I know. But look at the knobs on it!
我知道，你看它的咪咪多大
嘿
Emily's cousin kicked me out.
艾蜜莉的表妹 竟然把我赶出来
-What? -Why?
什么？ 为什么？
When you sublet from your wife's cousin...
跟老婆的表妹分租公寓
...then you divorce,sometimes the cousin wants his apartment back.
要是之后又离婚 表妹就会突然把房子要回去
Didn't you sign a lease?
怎么可以？你们没签约吗？
Who needs a lease when it's "family"?
谁跟亲戚租公寓还签约？
You can stay with us.
你可以跟我们住
Anything you need.
包在我们身上
But you have to let us know when you feel better...
你心情好一点就说一声
...so we can make fun of your hair.
好让我们取笑你的鸡窝头
You got it.
没问题
Thanks,I really appreciate this. I'm going to get packing again.
谢谢你们，我太感激了
我得回去打包行李了
I've been moving around so much that I feel like a nomad.
我最近不断搬家 简直像是游民
-What? -He thought you said gonad.
怎么了？他以为你说的是“咪咪”
The One Where Ross Moves ln
本集播出：“自找苦吃”
rainystar压制iPod-MP4
If every place were this clean, it'd be tough making a living.
要是每家餐厅都跟你的一样干净
我就没饭吃了
Oh,Larry!
别说了，赖瑞
Do health inspectors work on commission?
卫生稽查员收佣金吗？
No,bribes.
不，不过收红包
-It's okay to laugh? -I was just kidding.
我可以笑吧？当然，我开玩笑啦
-I'll check the kitchen floor. -Knock yourself out.
我去检查厨房地板 请自便，赖瑞
I don't get violations. You could eat beans off that floor.
我绝对不会违规
地板干净到 豆子都能捡起来吃
But don't,because that'd be a violation.
别吃喔，否则你就违规了
Yummy!
真可口
Yeah,I'd let him check out my kitchen floor.
你说赖瑞？我也愿意让他检查我厨房地板
A ninety-eight.
98分
I deducted two points for not wearing your hat.
你没戴帽子所以扣两分
That is a Section 5 violation.
因为违反第五条规定
Now look,Larry,honey.
赖瑞，亲爱的
I wrote the book on Section 5.
第五条条文我是专家
You only need to wear it in the kitchen.
在厨房才要戴帽子
-Where's your hat? -ln the kitchen. I'll get it.
你的帽子呢？
在厨房，我进去拿
There's the two points!
扣两分
You should really read that book you wrote.
专家也不过如此嘛
You saw the hat in the kitchen and knew she'd go in hatless to get it.
你看到帽子在厨房
知道她进去时没戴帽子
You could have your own health inspector detective show.
你可以当卫生稽查员 兼侦探了
I don't know about that.
你太客气了
But then I could be your sidekick,Voonda.
我可以演你的助手薇达
Maybe I could ask Voonda to dinner sometime?
薇达可以留电话给我 我就能约她出去吃饭
She would love that...
她一定很开心
...since you know all the clean places to eat.
因为你知道哪家餐厅才卫生
I'll call you.
我再打给你 好
He's so funny!
他真幽默
“中央咖啡馆”
Thank you.
谢了 谢谢
How's Ross doing since all the Emily stuff?
罗斯还好吧？ 还在为艾蜜莉伤心吗？
He's not great.
心情不太好
But he's dealing with it. Wait,you're not
不过还死不了 等等，你该不会…
拜托，不可能
I can't get started with all that Ross stuff again.
我不可能再跟罗斯交往
He'll be screwed up for a long time.
他还要失魂落魄大半年哩
Besides,I don't go for guys right after they get divorced.
况且你也知道 我不喜欢刚离婚的男人
Right,you only go for them five minutes before they get married.
对，快结婚的人你才要
-Two pounds of mocha java. -It's Danny.
我要两磅爪哇摩卡咖啡 是丹尼
Are you going to go out again?
你们还会出去吗？
I don't know. He hasn't called since we went out.
不知道 上次出去一次之后 他就没再打给我
I see him in the hallway. We flirt. I'm all:
我们只在走廊上打情骂俏
我笑得花枝乱颤
And then nothing.
却没下文
嘿
Wow,thirsty.
你很渴吧？
I'm having a party on Saturday. Sort of a housewarming thing.
我周六要办派对 庆祝我搬新家
-Fun. -Great!
真有意思 真好
I'm looking forward to it.
我也希望周六赶快到
See you!
那我走了
So I guess we won't be warming his house.
看来他新家不欢迎我们
All right,I see what he's doing.
很好，我知道他在玩什么把戏
He's not asking me out because he wants me to ask him out.
他故意不约我 因为他要我主动约他
And you won't do that.
可是你不鸟他
That's right!
没错
Because that would give him the control.
否则主导权就落在他手里
So now he comes up with this "I've got a party" thing...
他现在故意说什么要办派对
...to get me to hint for an invitation.
要我暗示他约我
Blew up in his face,didn't it?
可是我当场给他好看
So there is no party?
所以他根本没有要办派对
No,there's a party. There's a party.
有，当然有
But the power?
不过谁是老大
That is still up for grabs.
还不知道哩
You follow me?
你听得懂吗？
I think so.
应该吧
So he won't invite you to his party because he likes you?
你说他喜欢你 所以故意不约你
Exactly!
就是这样
Then why didn't he invite me?
可是他为什么不约我？
To throw me off.
故意吊我胃口
罗斯
Hey,roomies!
亲爱的室友
I love what you've done with the place.
你把家里阎玫谜嫖萝
I know it's a lot of boxes.
我知道箱子堆得到处都是
-I appreciate you letting me stay here.
-Not a problem.
我要再次感谢你们收容我 没问题
Since you'll be here a while...
既然你要在这里住一阵子
...we could put your name on the answering machine.
干脆录一段你的留言
I hope you don't mind...
是啊 希望你们别介意
...but I kind of already jazzed it up a little.
我已经录了一段
Check it out.
你们听
We will
我们一定
We will call you back
一定会回你电话
Pretty cool.
很酷吧？
-You're fake laughing too,right? -The tears are real.
你也是假笑吧？不过眼泪是真的
You look beautiful this evening.
你今晚真漂亮
Show me the badge again.
再给我看一次徽章
Shiny.
真是闪闪发亮
You mind if I wash up? Who knows where these have been?
我去洗个手
谁晓得这两个宝贝碰过什么
You are just nonstop!
你真是宝到不行
-We're out of here. -Why?
我们必须立刻走 为什么？
I saw 1 0 violations. I'm shutting this place down!
我刚经过厨房就看到十项违规
我要勒令他们停业
-You have the power to do that? -This does.
你办得到吗？ 有这个就可以
Shut it down.
那就让他们停业吧
嘿
What are you doing?
你做什么？
Nothing.
没什么
You built a fort,didn't you?
你造了一个城堡？
Kind of.
差不多
Oh,my God! The air purifier. Ross' air purifier.
天啊，是他的空气清净器
All I heard for four years through college was....
我大学四年只听得到…
You should have gone out once in a while.
老兄，你不该只闷在宿舍里
-I hate this thing! -Come on,Chandler.
我讨厌这东西
钱德
Ross is our friend. He needs us right now.
罗斯是我们的好友 他现在需要我们帮忙
So why don't you be a grownup and come watch TV in the fort?
成熟点，进来城堡看电视吧
Can't believe that Larry closed down Churman's. I love that place.
赖瑞竟然勒令楚门餐厅停业
我很喜欢那家餐厅
You should have heard about all their violations.
你应该听听他们有哪些违规
Larry said that they should call it Vermin's.
赖瑞说他们该改名蟑螂餐厅
That guy just plain kills me.
那家伙实在太耍宝了
I wanted to invite you to the party.
我来请你们参加明晚的派对
Thanks,I'll try to stop by.
谢了，我们有时间就过去
Actually,I think I'm going to be busy.
不过我可能有事
You are?
是吗？
Remember,I've got that gala?
对，我上次跟你说要参加比赛
What's the gala for?
什么比赛？
It's a regatta gala.
赛船会
Do you sail?
你会开帆船？
No,but I support it.
不会，可是我赞助比赛
I hope I see you tomorrow night. Take care.
好吧，明晚见咯 保重，再见
Walked right into that one, didn't he?
我这招打得他满脸豆花
What one?
哪一招？
You wanted him to invite you and he did.
你希望他邀你参加派对 他也来啦
He waited until the last minute. So if I said yes...
可是他等到最后一刻才来 如果我答应
...he'd know I had nothing better to do than wait for his invitation.
他就知道 我没事可做等着去他家
But I said no...
但是我说不去
...which puts me back in the driver's seat.
所以还是我咨戏
So the ball is in his court?
正点，所以换他出招咯？
Ball?
出招？
No,there's no ball.
他没招可出了
Hey,Phoebe,you want to join us?
菲比，你吃不吃？
-Oh,sure,yeah. Where is this from? -It's from Sun Ling's.
好啊，哪里买的？ 三林餐厅
Oh,Larry just told me something about Sun Ling.
赖瑞跟我提过三林中菜
Oh,no,thank you.
算了，多谢
Joey,please.
乔伊，麻烦你
Sorry.
对不起
Hello,children.
小鬼们
You want to play some foosball? Please?
要不要玩桌足球？求求你？
好吧 不…
We moved the table into my room because of all the boxes.
游戏桌搬进我房间了
因为外面太多箱子
Come on!
进来吧
I have one question.
我有个问题
What is the deal with this?
这是什么碗糕？
Bye-bye,little puppet Joey hand?
小布偶乔伊说再见？
No,the quiet down thing.
不是，叫我闭嘴的手势
You mean this.
你是说这样啊
I don't know how much more I can take.
我不知道我还能憋多久
Did you know he taped over my Baywatch tape with a show about bugs?
他竟然拿我的海滩游侠录影带 去录什么怪小虫
My God!
What if that had been porn?
要是里面录的是A片呢？
All right,this may be tough...
别激动，或许你憋得很难过
...but it's Ross. I survived college with him.
可是他是老友罗斯
我跟他大学住四年都没死了
I guess I can hold out a little longer.
我或许还可以再忍一阵子
Let's have a game.
来玩吧 好
不要… 万岁
Fellas?
两位
So he's out of here.
他非走不可
Got anything to eat? I went to Jono's and it was closed.
这里有没有东西可吃？
我刚去强诺买鸡块 那里竟然停业了
I took Larry there,but it was all violated,so we shut it down.
我带赖瑞去，餐厅不合规定 我们勒令他们停业
If this guy keeps closing our favorite places,where will we eat?
菲比，这家伙不断关掉 大家喜欢去的餐馆 以后我们上哪吃饭？
I don't know. Clean places?
不晓得，干净的地方？
Yum!
It's Danny.
是丹尼
Don't let him in! I'm supposed to be at a gala.
别让他进来，我现在 应该去看帆船赛了
We'll be right there. Can't you say it's later?
我们马上过去 不能说大赛还没开始吗？
What kind of a regatta gala starts at night?
什么？哪种帆船在晚上比赛？
The fake kind.
假的那种
-I need a ladle. You got a ladle? -We have a ladle.
嗨，我想借个勺子，你有吗？
我们有
See you at the party.
谢了，待会儿见 好
You know what Larry would say? He'd say,"See you ladle."
你们知道赖瑞会怎么回答吗？ 他会说，“杓后见”
I'm done. You want anything? Sports? International?
我看完了，你要看吗，罗斯？ 有体育、国际
Apartment listings?
租屋版
I'll take sports.
我要体育版
Mine!
我要
All right,international.
那就国际版好了
That's mine too.
我也要
I'm ltalian.
我是意大利裔
I could check apartment listings, though there's never anything here.
不然看看租屋广告吧 不过报上向来没吉屋
Not even on page seven?
第7页也没有吗？
You're right. Here's an affordable place.
有耶，你说得对 有个地方价钱很公道
Two-bedroom,close to work. It's available in five weeks.
两房、上班也近 可是还要五周才能搬进去
What about that circled one?
圈起来那个呢？
It's kind of expensive for a studio.
不知道耶，就套房来说有点贵
But it's available now.
可是现在就能搬进去
Isn't it?
对不对？
Yes,it is.
的确是
Let's go look at it!
我们去看看
There we go!
好，我们走 走吧
Guys,would you chip in for some new air filters for the purifier?
对了，忘了告诉你们
可不可以大家分摊买滤芯？
I mean,after all, we are all using it.
毕竟空气清净器大家都有用到
Let's go quicker!
快点走 好
Oh,my God!
天啊
Look at this kitchen/bathroom.
你们看这个厨房…兼浴室
That's great! So you can cook while in the tub.
太棒了，可以一边煮饭 一边洗澡
Somebody was using his head.
房东真是太聪明了
Let's check out the rest of the place.
再看看其他地方
I think this is it.
就这么大了
I don't know. Maybe we should keep looking.
我们应该看看别间公寓
But this place is available now.
可是这地方马上就能搬进来
You don't want to be stuck with us for five weeks.
对啊，你不会愿意 继续跟我们住五周
So you think I should take this place?
你觉得我应该租下？
It's perfect!
这里很棒啊
How about you?
你呢？
Kitchen,slash,bathroom.
这里有厨房兼浴室耶
I see what you guys are saying.
好吧，我懂了
I'll go downstairs and fill out an application.
我下楼填申请表
We are bad people.
我们是坏人
He knew we were trying to get rid of him.
他知道我们想赶他走
Could we get a bathtub in our kitchen?
我们厨房能不能装浴缸？
Ready for dinner?
要去吃饭了吗？
-Absolutely. -Great.
好啊
You wanted to go to the ltalian place on Bleecker St.?
你上次不是说要去布里克街 那家意大利餐厅？
I love that place!
我爱死那里了
So,no.
所以…不行
How about Mama Lozetti's?
“李赛提老妈”呢？
Sure.
没问题
How long has that milk been sitting out?
不知道那瓶牛奶放多久了？
No,this place is totally healthy.
这地方非常干净
This milk is mine. I bought this today...
那瓶牛奶是我的 今天买的
...because I was thirsty for milk, you know?
我突然想喝牛奶
Okay,let's go.
我们走吧
Hey,buddy.
老兄
Health Code 1 1 B requires that refuse be taken out the back exit.
你知道卫生规则 11条B款吗？ 垃圾应该从后门拿出去
But then I have to go all the way around.
可是这样就得从干洗店绕路
So you choose convenience over health?
你宁可方便也不顾卫生？
Would you be interested in a free coffee?
请你喝咖啡好吗？
Stop,Larry.
赖瑞，别这样
Can't you just be Larry and not Larry the health inspector guy?
你能不能别老想着工作？
It was exciting at first.
一开始还很刺激
But now,it's like,so where are we going to eat ever?
现在简直哪家餐厅也去不了
I suppose I could give him a warning.
不然我口头警告他好了
Thank you.
谢谢
Go,go!
快走啊
If,after dinner, you still need to bust someone...
要是吃饱饭后你还想抓人
...I know a hot dog vendor who picks his nose.
我知道哪个热狗摊老板 喜欢挖鼻子
Maybe we did good, helping Ross get back on his feet.
搞不好我们做的是好事 帮助罗斯早点恢复正常
That was a nice place.
况且那地方实在不错 是啊
No closet space,but he could hang his stuff out the window in a bag.
虽然柜子不多 不过可以用袋子装好挂在窗外
是啊
What do we do?
现在该怎么办？
I don't know.
不知道
Maybe pizza?
要吃披萨吗？
About Ross!
我说的是罗斯
喂
It's the apartment manager. Ross put us as references.
我是，是公寓经理 罗斯填我们当介绍人
Ross is the greatest guy. He's very reliable
罗斯绝对是好人 这人非常可靠
Of course,he has a big,huge dog that barks into the night.
不过他养了一支大狗 那支狗半夜叫个不停
Well,who doesn't love dogs?
谁不喜欢狗？
He's a tap dancer.
他是个踢踏舞者
Yes,some would say that is a lost art.
这的确是失传的艺术
He's a pimp!
他是皮条客
There you go. He's a pimp.
没错，就是皮条客
He's a big,tap-dancing pimp!
他是会跳踢踏舞的皮条客
喂
-Okay,honey,I'm ready. -What are you doing?
我准备好了 你穿这样干么？
I am going to wander into the party and I will be all,you know:
我要晃进派对 装做一副
"l don't need this, I'm coming from a regatta gala."
刚从帆船赛回来的样子
Did you get this out of a book?
你这是从书上学来的吗？
Monica,honey,this is as real as it gets.
亲爱的摩妮卡，书如人生啊
This is never going to work. He's right there.
该死，这可不行 他就站在那里
Just go say hi.
去打声招呼就行啦
I have to go downstairs and back up, as if I'm coming home from the gala.
不行，我得从楼下走上来 假装我刚从外面回来
So just go distract him. But don't be sexy.
你去引开他的注意力 但是别勾引他
丹尼
What's going on?
你好
This is a great party. Great food.
这个派对真不错，食物也很好
You know,most parties,it's all chips and salsa,chips and salsa.
大部分派对都只有薯片、辣酱 薯片、辣酱
So....
What's this?
这是什么？
Salad.
沙拉
喔
And what's this?
这又是什么？
Bread.
面包
Aren't you a chef?
你不是厨师吗？
嘿，瑞秋
Right,tonight was your party.
对了，你今晚要办派对
You look great! I'm glad you made it.
你穿得真漂亮 幸好你赶回来了
Well,you know, the gala had to end sometime.
比赛总不能没完没了
Don't go anywhere. I'll be right back.
你别走开，我马上回来
没问题
Whose court is the ball in now?
你说现在换谁出招啦？
I thought there wasn't a ball.
你不是说他没招可出？
Come on. He's glad I came. He doesn't want me to go anywhere.
拜托，他很高兴我来了 而且还叫我别走开
Ball's flying all over the place.
我们两个现在是你来我往
This is my friend,Tom.
瑞秋，这是我朋友汤姆
This is the girl I told you about.
这就是我跟你提过的小姐
Come on! You telling people about me?
拜托，你跟人提过我？
I think you two could really hit it off.
你们一定会来电
I'm gonna go mingle.
我去跟朋友哈拉了
So you work at Bloomingdale's? My mom calls it "Bloomies."
你在布鲁明代尔百货上班？
我妈都说那里是“布明儿”
At ease,soldier!
真不错，稍息，大兵
I'm sorry?
什么？
You can just drop the act. I know what's going on.
没关系，汤姆，你别装了 我知道你们搞什么鬼
You're Danny's wingman,right?
你是丹尼的好友对不对？
You guys are best buds,frat bros.
你们交情老、感情好
I'm going to go talk to a friend.
我要去…找朋友
Yeah,you go talk to your friend.
请便，去找你朋友吧
Go tell him,"Nice try."
告诉他，“这招漂亮”
He just keeps lobbing them up...
他真是出招连连
...and I keep knocking them right out of the park.
不过我可是招招都破
I think I need a drink.
我想喝杯饮料 我也要
Ninety-eight...
98、
...ninety-nine...
99、
...one hundred!
Okay. Go.
走吧
Dude,I'm telling you,I'm fine.
告诉你，我没问题
Here we go,here we go.
我扶住你了
嘿 嘿
So I didn't get that apartment. Some problem with my application.
我没租到那间公寓 我的申请作业出状况
You're kidding?
哪有可能？ 不会吧
But Phoebe said I could stay at her place for a while,so....
不过菲比答应让我搬去跟她住
Well,you can't stay with Phoebe. We're roomies.
你不能住菲比家 我们可是室友耶
You don't need me taking up all your space.
我不能再子媚忝枪寓
We got plenty of space. There's still some by that speaker.
反正这里大得很 音箱旁边还有空地
Please,just stay.
住下来吧 对
Are you sure?
你们确定？ 当然
-Definitely. -You have to stay.
罗斯，你非住下来不可
好吧 就这么办
So I'm a pimp,huh?
你们说我是皮条客？
It's okay.
算了
Sometimes I can be a pain in the ass.
我知道我有时候很顾人怨
But just talk to me. Tell me if something bothers you.
不过你们可以直说 明白告诉我哪里做得不好
And I'll do everything I can to keep my annoying habits just....
我可以尽量改掉惹人嫌的习惯
Well,I see you've had a very productive day.
显然你今天过得很充实
The cowboy hat's a little much.
不过戴牛仔帽也太扯了吧？
Come on,it's fun!
进来一起玩
All right.
好吧
Isn't this a woman's hat?
这不是女人的帽子吗？
Stop talking crazy,and make us tea!
还不赶快闭嘴去泡茶？